Guide to the Stanford University, Asian Survey Committee, Asian Survey Project Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Asian Survey Committee, Asian survey project records
1951 1951
SC0045
Stanford University. Asian Survey Committee.
1.5 Linear feet
Correspondence and minutes of meetings, progress reports, and recordings of meetings and conversations of a group of Stanford University faculty members led by Carl Spaeth and funded by the Ford Foundation. This group, the Asian Survey Committee, was organized to initiate, direct, and coordinate a nation-wide survey on the status of Asian studies in the United States, measure this work against the scope of current national needs, and record problems, requirements, and possible solutions. Correspondents and members of the Committee include Harold Henry Fisher, Arthur Wright, and Mary Wright.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Transferred by the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace, Stanford, California.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence and minutes of meetings, progress reports, and recordings of meetings and conversations of a group of Stanford University faculty members led by Carl Spaeth and funded by the Ford Foundation. This group, the Asian Survey Committee, was organized to initiate, direct, and coordinate a nation-wide survey on the status of Asian studies in the United States, measure this work against the scope of current national needs, and record problems, requirements, and possible solutions. Correspondents and members of the Committee include Harold Henry Fisher, Arthur Wright, and Mary Wright.
Access Terms
Fisher, Harold H. (Harold Henry), 1890-1975; Ford Foundation; Gardner, John.; Harris, C. P.; Ike, Nakamura.; North, Robert.; Spaeth, Carl B.; Stanford University. Asian Survey Committee.; Stegner, Wallace Earle, 1909-1993; Toynbee, Arnold Joseph, 1889-1975.; Wright, Arthur.; Wright, Mary.; Asia --Study and teaching.; Memoranda.; Minutes.; Notes.; Reports.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Survey papers 1, 2, 9 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fisher, H.H. "Notes on Project Kosmos" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rothwell, C. Easton. "Some tentative Ideas on the Far Eastern Project," 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Possibilities of American Aid to Educational Institutions of South Asia and Middle East" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter: Mary Wright to Carl Spaeth, Feb. 5, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Ford Report (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter: Sterling to Mr. Hoffman (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - President's Far Eastern Project – assignments (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Interdepartmental letters to Robert North (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Survey paper 3: Prospectus by Nakamura Ike, Feb. 15, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Survey paper 5: Prospectus by Arthur Wright, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Survey Paper 6b: Prospectus by Mary Wright, Feb. 19, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Survey paper 7: Draft of a Substantive Investigation re Ideologies and Political Movements in the Modern Far East; with comments by Carl Spaeth (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Survey paper 7: Radicalism and Conservatism – revision (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Survey paper 8: Strategy and Tactics in Soviet Political Policies Toward Asia (second draft) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Survey paper 10: A Survey of Publication Media for Writings on the Far East (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Survey Paper 11: Current Research on the Far East (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Survey Paper 12: Library Resources for the Study of the Modern Far East (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Survey paper 13: Observations on an Approach to the Far Eastern Project by C. Easton Rothwell, Feb. 27, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Survey paper 14: List of projects for consideration (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Survey paper 15: The Use of Personnel and Resources, Mar. 5, 1951 – first draft by Arthur Wright and second draft by Tom Smith (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Survey paper 15a: Training Programs, Mar. 12, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Survey paper 16: Patterns of Thought in Eastern Asia – first draft by Arthur Wright (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Survey paper 17: The Japanese Elite, Theoretical Considerations (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Survey paper 18: A Project on the Development of Chinese Historical Thinking; includes letter from Arnold J. Toynbee to Prof. Wright, Dec. 6, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Survey paper 19: Japanese Foreign Office Documents, by Tom Smith, Mar. 12, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Survey paper 20: Introduction to Series of Additional Research Projects by Mary Wright (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Survey paper 21: Project Introduction, Geographical Scope by H. H. Fisher, Mar. 15, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Survey paper 22: Publication Media – revision (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Survey paper 23: Robert North's sub-introduction re Need to Understand Far Eastern Problems (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Survey paper 24: Lack of Knowledge about Asia, part one first draft by Nivison, Mar. 22, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Survey paper 24: Lack of Knowledge about Asia, part one second draft (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Survey paper 24: Lack of Knowledge about Asia, part one third draft with notes on an advisory board (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Survey paper 25: Intellectual Co-operation with Asia, Mar. 16, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Survey paper 26: The Middle East: Problems for Research by C. P. Harris, Mar. 22, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Survey paper 27: An Advisory Board of Consultants, by C. Easton Rothwell, Mar. 23, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Survey paper 28: Strategy and Tactics of Communism in Iran, by C. P. Harris, Mar. 23, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Survey paper 29: proposal to establish Central Editorial Office (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Survey paper 30: Nationalism and reform in the Arab world, by C. P. Harris, Mar. 24, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Survey paper 31: Asian Background Material for Teaching and Textbooks and Editorial Use, by H. H. Fisher, Mar. 24, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Phase I Minutes of meetings, Feb.-Mar, 1951, with some memoranda and correspondence by Arthur Wright, H. H Fisher, Wallace Stegner, Mary Wright (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Phase Two Minutes of meetings, April 1951 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Phase Two Finances (requisitions), May 1951 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Phase Two Agenda, Eastern meetings (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Phase Two Miscellaneous reports and conversations (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Foundation Appropriations for the Far East and Pacific Area, 1945-49 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Research on Economic Development, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Includes reports, notes, correspondence, and memoranda of Eugene Staley, Arthur Wright, Knight Biggerstaff, Woodbridge Bingham, H. H. Fisher and others.
  - Correspondence, proposals, and memoranda, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Includes Proposal for Far Eastern Training Program at Stanford; proposal for opening American Section of Indian Council of World Affairs, New Delhi; and Ethel M. Ewing's memorandum concerning effective education in the far east.
  - China Journey, Jan. 24 to July 27, 1945, Franz Michael, Seattle, Sept. 1947 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, notes, reports, and memoranda of conversations, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Correspondents include Derk Bodde, Charles Gardner, Owen Lattimore, and H. Arthur Steiner. Conversations are with Francis Russell, Rothwell, Howard, George Ball, Herbert Elliston, Ed Murrow, Graves, Fairbank, Richard Frye, Philip K. Hitti, and Douglas Oliver.
  - Correspondence, memoranda, proposals, and other documents, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Correspondents include H. R. Isaacs, George E. Taylor, C. Wilbur Martin, W. L. Holland, Carl Spaeth, Garnet R. Garrison, and Rayford W. Logan.
  - Workbook 8, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Includes memos of committee members, progress reports, and Survey of College Courses Dealing with U.S. Policy Toward the Far and Middle East; volume has an index.
  - Workbook 8, Par II, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Includes progress reports and accounts of meetings and conversations
  - Assorted documents including index, progress reports, and summary of interviews, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Progress Reports and accounts of meetings and conversations, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 47)